[SPEAKER_00] Okay, so I checked some of the homework, Alhamdulillah. I want more of us to be doing the homework. I know, obviously, it's not like school. You're not going to be in trouble. You're not going to be sent to the office. You're not going to be suspended if you don't do your homework. But at the end of the day, it's benefiting us, right? I'm not getting any benefit if you're doing your homework or if you don't do your homework. It's going to benefit you. So if you really want mastery of the Arabic language, the more practice you do, the more Inshallah you will be well versed. So Inshallah, just try to pick up on the homework. Inshallah, it's not too much, right? It shouldn't have taken very long at all. For those who did it, how long did it take you? Anybody? Two minutes. Two minutes? Two minutes. Five minutes? No. An hour. Okay, Inshallah.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. Well, for a lot of us, it took 10, 15, 20 minutes. If you want to be a perfectionist, then good. Even better. The more time you spend, the more benefit, Inshallah. But we want everybody to try to start doing the homework, Inshallah. Now, for the other homework, the extra homework, I have to have that even. Can somebody give an example? Yeah. Okay, Inshallah, very good. So it's talking about, that is, it was describing, the ayah before was describing the punishment of Jahannam. So Allah said, We discussed in the previous lesson as to why would be used for things that are going to happen the year after. For example, Sorry about Sorry. Which means that that is the day of truth. Right? So we talked about that the word is used because
[SPEAKER_00] the time is far away from now. So in the same way, That would be used because Jahannam is far from now. And the word is used. Okay. Another example? Surah Yusuf. Surah Yusuf. Ayah one or two. I am not happy with the... Surah Yusuf. That is. Remember when Yusuf said in the Father's visit, he dreamed of a kid? I am not exactly sure. No, I don't think that is used. Surah Rahat? Surah Rahat. Okay, but that's a little different It'll be a little confusing if we try to explain that But it's good
[SPEAKER_00] After Allah describes some of the tidings He said Yeah, good Allah talks about That Allah sent amongst the unlettered ones A prophet And some other details he mentions And he says That is the grace of Allah That is referring to the thing that he mentioned previously Yeah, very good That example we discussed last time We discussed as to why The word dadiqah was used rather than hada Who can remember the answer? Yeah, it's not so very good Because the book is so exalted It's as if it's at a high level That we can't even reach Yeah, good There's many examples we can give But the main
[SPEAKER_00] point that we understand is what? Was it the reason hada and dadiqah? I think that's close Dadiqah is horrible Good, mashallah Other than that, they're both the same in two things What are the two things? That they're both the same in? Singular Singular Second thing? Masculine But they're different in the third thing, which is? Close Yeah One is for close And the other is for far Alright, very good, mashallah Now, I have some questions for you guys To review the vocabulary So this time I'm a little bit more prepared Before I was drawing that picture on the board And then I was using my phone I was searching it But that's fine It takes some time So I searched it before And I brought my iPad So you can see better So, ma hada? Okay, rajun is correct Rajun means what? Man, okay Another, somebody said Taajur Good Hada, taajur I'm sorry, you guys
[SPEAKER_00] Taajur I actually searched for a while I couldn't find it Because there were a bunch of guys in suits I'm like, how are you supposed to know what it means? You could be a lawyer Yeah, you could be a lawyer too Yeah, hada, taajur Taajur means what? Merchant Merchant or businessman, right? Hada, taajur, okay Man, hada? Hada, tabeebun Nah, hada, tabeebun This is a shaykh, Dr. Hussein Abu Sattar He's the first doctor that came to my mind But he's, mashallah, he's a doctor He's also a shaykh He's a very accomplished doctor So he wrote a textbook in pathology So I just searched a picture of him So this is Dr. Hussein So hada, tabeebun Okay Man, hada? Mashallah Hada, waladun What is waladun? Boy, yeah, male child Good Hada, waladun, okay Ahada, baytun?
[SPEAKER_00] Nah, you can say it Or hada, you can say it Hada, masjid al-fiz It's not wrong Ahada, himalun? Nah, nah Ahada, kalman Sorry Ma hada? Hada, jama'at I took this picture myself You killed it Ma hada? Hada, jama'at Hada, jama'at Hada, jama'at Hada, say again Hada, same animal Hada, he's talking He's talking, he's talking, okay Ahada, kelbon? Hada, kelbon Hada, kelbon, okay, good Man, hada? Man, hada
[SPEAKER_00] They use man or what? No, man No Huh? You can't. No, it's not a good thing. It doesn't help you. Okay, so what are we supposed to use? Ma. Ma, right, good. So, ma hada. Hadha. Hadha. Hadha from ma, okay good. Ahada qalamun? Hadha. Hadha. Hadha. Hadha. Hadha. Hadja, yeah, la, hadha, hadja. Yes. Okay, all right, I think that's enough testing of previous lessons, I think you guys got the concepts. Oh yeah, a few ayahs about maan. Somebody, we mentioned that again. Anybody have any ayahs about maan? In Surah Al-Urk, ayah 16. Wa minal nasi man yaqul, amal na'i illahi wa bil nil wa a'kiru wa ma'nil. Good, mashaAllah. Right from the beginning of the Qur'an. From amongst people are those, so maan can be used for singular, or you can use it for singular in this context, or it can also be used for plural.
[SPEAKER_00] So the context that, brother Salim brought, the ayah that he brought, is plural, right? From amongst people are those who, they say we believe in Allah, so who, right? So the main thing is maan means who, it's referring to somebody with intellect, all right? Okay. Let's talk about the context of whoever, punishes with the same thing that he was punished with, meaning he takes revenge, right? So we're talking about that context. So maan is used because somebody with intellect. Whoever does any evil deeds, then you will not be recompensed except by something similar to it. So again, it's used in the context that somebody has intellect. So maan is for intellect. That's the main thing we want to keep in our minds, inshaAllah. All right.
[SPEAKER_00] Now, this upcoming lesson is an important lesson. So before we get into the lesson itself, right? Well, actually, let's read the lesson. Who can read the lesson? Somebody different, somebody that hasn't read yet. But we need you to read loudly. Loudly, very loudly. Al-damas al-thalizu. Al-baytu al-baytu. Al-kidab al-kidab. Qalam al-qalam. Jamal al-jamal. Okay, before we even discuss, there's a lot to unpack and discuss here. But before we even do so, what do you think that the author is trying to highlight by mentioning these two words together? Somebody, just guess, take an educated guess, please. Based on what you can see in front
[SPEAKER_00] of you. No, I thought, you already studied, so no. Yeah. From something general to something specific. Something general to something specific, okay. All right. What else is the author highlighting? It seems like for each word, he's adding alif, laf, so al and al. Okay. The ending of the word is changing. Very good. So he's adding al, and the end of word is changing. It's changing in what way? What's changing about the word when he adds al? Tan. No tan. No tan. No, not . That's not the difference. In terms of sound, what's the difference that's coming? Fesh, not tanween. Yeah, like fesh, which is dhamma, right? So in the situation where it doesn't have alif, laf, then there is only, there's two dhammas. There's a tanween, right? Now, as soon as you add alif, laf, what happens? One dhamma gets dropped. Yeah. You get it? So it was baytun,
[SPEAKER_00] which is two peishes, two dhammas put together, right? Yeah. As soon as you put al, then one dhamma drops. Everybody got that? Yeah. Right, so that's basically what he's highlighting, right? You might not be able to see the two dhammas, so I'll just put it for you here. So here, there's two dhammas, right? Now, but as soon as you add al, then you only have one dhamma. Now, this is a rule that there's absolutely no exceptions to. Whenever you have al in the beginning of a word in Arabic, you can never have a tanween. You guys know what a tanween is, right? Yeah. Tanween is when there's two of the same letter. Un, an, in, right? You can never have a tanween. You can never have a tanween. Tanween and al are the same word, right?
[SPEAKER_00] So you can never have, you can never, this is impossible. Al baytun is impossible in Arabic grammar, right? So just, as soon as you see that somewhere, you know it's a mistake, or if somebody reads it like that, you know that they have made a mistake, alright? So just know that. Al and tanween never ever come together. Everybody understand that? Yeah. Right? Should I write it down, or you guys can write it down? I can't see it. I can't move the... Oh, the board? Yeah, the board so that everybody can... I don't know if that's possible. Maybe move this way. What's in front? Oh yeah, you can move this too, yeah. This doesn't need to be here. You can move it to the side. Here. Can you see it now? Yeah, I can see it. Yeah, but you can't see it. Yeah, I think it wasn't that, I think you were covering it. Oh, alright.
[SPEAKER_00] So, baytun, right, we see it had two tanweens, and then al baytu, right? So this will never happen, so you have to only have one thumma, okay? That's in every scenario. Whenever you have al in a word, it can never ever have tanween. Okay, now what this indicates, what this means, and we'll get into that, but we're just reading a lesson. I just want you guys to start thinking for yourself. And when you're reading the lesson before we come to class, start using your mind, thinking, what is the author trying to explain to you? Don't cheat and go to the English translation, because there's no reason to make an explanation there. I told you, we're not relying on the English translation, right? We're not allowed to go to the English translation, right? We're going to purely learn Arabic through Arabic, and so on. Alright? How many of you guys checked the Arabic-English lesson out before this lesson? Before we started? No. Okay. So... Okay, you can keep reading. We'll
[SPEAKER_00] go on. Okay. Just note that alqalamu, right? It doesn't say alqalamun, right? And when you read the Qur'an, just note this point, and I challenge you to find a word that has al, and it also has tanween on it. You won't be able to find it, right? Just note that when you're reading the Qur'an, just see, okay, there's an al here, let me see, maybe something's wrong with this one. But again, I'll teach you in one of the next few days, alright? Okay, so alqalamu maqsood. Okay. Alright. We'll explain what each of these things means. We're just going to read those. So is that just how the Qur'an is written? No, this is a general rule in Arabic. Okay. Yeah. Alqalamu means that the pen is broken. Yes. Good. Alqalamu means that the pen is broken. Okay.
[SPEAKER_00] Alright. Ok. Now these are three different sentences. Alqalamu means what? What does alqalamu mean? Pen. Pen. Pen. Good, masha'Allah. Maksoor means broken, okay. So you can add up to your vocabulary. Maksoor means broken, okay. Maksoor means broken. So that's why you see the drawing is a bit crude, but that's why there's a little line in the middle of the pencil, and to signify that it's broken. Alright. الباب. What is الباب? Door, right? And we had الباب in the first lesson. الباب مفتوح, right? Open. Do you guys see a correlation between the word مفتوح and one of the words that we learned recently? مفتاح What is مفتاح? مفتاح Key. So you see there's something common between... مفتوح says it means open. And مفتاح means key. So there seems to
[SPEAKER_00] be some correlation, and it's from the same root letters. فتاح Right? And if we know فتح also means what? Anybody know? فتح Opening. فاتح فاتح So the word opening is common between all these letters. Now how exactly that fits together, that's something we're going to learn in the next lesson. As time goes on. So once you start noting these connections, once you start making these connections in your own mind, as you learn the rules, you'll be able to fit it. Oh, that's why this is مفتوح. It's not random that مفتاح is on that pattern and مفتوح is on that pattern. It's not like I just randomly chose it. It's actually a methodology behind it. So that's what we're going to learn as time goes on. So anyways, مفتوح means? Open. Open, right? الباب مفتوح Okay. الولد جالس الولد Boy. Boy. جالس means? Sitting. Sitting. جالس. What does
[SPEAKER_00] المدرس mean? Teacher. Teacher. And what does و mean? Type. Okay, what type, what family does it belong to? Yeah, حرف العطف. The connecting letters. Right? و. And المدرس is teacher, right? و. And مفتوح means standing. Okay, now I didn't intend, I don't want this lesson to just be a bunch of vocabulary, right? But there's a certain sentence structure that's being explained here. But now this is where we'll go into the rules behind it, right? So if you guys read the lesson that I posted on the group, I'm not going to, we don't read the whole thing. You can read it after, inshallah. But the general idea that that lesson was conveying is that in Arabic, the word in Arabic language can be divided into three types. Okay, I'm going to write it down.
[SPEAKER_00] Sorry, I'm writing very small. I'm going to write a little bigger. And كلمة means word, right? Is that too small? Should I write it bigger? A little bit bigger. All right, so let me see. Okay, now الكلمة means the word, right? So the word in the Arabic language can be classified into three different categories, okay? What are these three categories? The first category is اسم.
[SPEAKER_00] So اسم, as many of you know, means name, right? For example, مسمك, what is your name, right? But اسم in this context means a noun. Okay, now what is a noun? In English, when we learn grammar, when we say such and such thing is a noun, what does that mean? What does that indicate towards? Person, place, thing, or idea, right? And then in Arabic, what's also included is adjectives and adverbs. These are also included in اسم. So I'm going to write all that down right now.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, so this is a Netflix right now. Okay, so this is a Netflix right now. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. So, I don't know about the way. Wherever I go, I'm not in the way. So, now what is the example? Because if this is too vague for you, let's go into it, right? A person, right? So a person, a name would be like, Muhammad, right, is a person, right? Mother is a person. مدرس. مدرس is also a person, right? مدرس means what? مدرس means what? A person. Teacher, right? That's also a person, right? And what I do, like we learned, which means child, that's also a person. So these are all examples of an اسم, right? But it's a person. Then, a place, right? A mess to you, right? Basically, everything that we've learned so far is,
[SPEAKER_00] it all falls in this category. That's why I like the way this book works. It doesn't confuse you. Some books, they'll bring all different types. So they'll bring the affair, a part of اسم, all at the same time. And you're like, oh, I don't know. Like, we're confused. But so far, all we've went through is اسم. Because very, very few حافظ about, we don't need to worry about that. Basically, everything we've come across so far is, it comes in this category of اسم, which is اسم. Okay? So a place, yeah, right? Or even a proper, do you guys know what it means to get a proper noun? Do you know what a proper noun is? A proper noun is basically the name of something, right? Yeah. So for example, Egypt, right, is a proper noun because it's the name of a country, right? Yeah. Masjid Hamza, for example, would be a proper noun because it's talking about a specific masjid. If you were just to say, masjid, masjidun or al-masjidun, that would not be a proper noun because it's not a name of a particular masjid, right? Similarly, if you were just to say, mudarris or al-mudarris, then that's not a proper noun because it's not a specific teacher.
[SPEAKER_00] If you were to say, Sa'im, that would be a proper noun because you're talking about the name of a specific person, right? So this includes both, proper noun and a specific noun. I mean, there's a difference in those two. We'll get to inshallah later. Then, a thing, right? A thing is obvious. There's so many things. Give me an example of a thing that we've learned so far in Arabic. Qadamun. Qadamun. Okay, good. Any more examples? Kitabun. Kitabun. Good. Misaf and Laban. Good, inshallah. Alright. These are all things, right? Now, an idea is like, you know, justice, happiness, education, right? These are all ideas, but they're also considered nouns in Arabic. Then, in English as well. Then, in Arabic as well. Then, an adjective, right? Tal. Tawil. Right? We didn't learn that yet, right? Yeah. Tal is also, even though in English that's not considered a noun, right? An adjective is a separate category. But in Arabic, sorry, in English it's a separate category, but in Arabic, an adjective is considered also a noun, right?
[SPEAKER_00] An adverb slowly, but that's not really common in Arabic. Okay. So, but these are the categories that fall under ism. Then, affair. Affair. Affair is a second thing. Affair, that's a singular version. Affair refers to a verb. What's a verb? An action. An action. An indicator of an action, right? So, it could be a past tense verb, something that happened in the past, somebody did something in the past, right? Right. He hit. Right? So, hitting is an action, right? It's not a person, place, thing, idea, any of these things, right? Hitting is an action, something that you did. You get it? So, that's under this category of a verb, right? Now, one difference between a verb and an ism in Arabic is that
[SPEAKER_00] in the verb, you get the notion of a time. What does that mean? So, when you're doing an action, it has to be done at a specific time. Either it was done in the past or it was done in the present. Okay. Or it will be done in the future. Right? Whereas an ism, you don't, it doesn't indicate towards time at all. Right? You're just saying it's a person. But you don't know if that person exists in the past, present or future. Right? The word itself doesn't indicate towards any time period. You get it? But the verb, as soon as you say the verb, automatically will indicate towards a time period. Right? Don't get too confused. Inshallah, we'll get, I'm just giving you a concept for now. Right? When we actually get to the verb, we're not getting to verbs yet. The verb will come up. The verb will come after a lot of lessons. So don't worry. Don't stress yourself. But this is just so we have a conceptualization of how the Arabic language works. This is a very foundational lesson that we're having. So, again, a verb, it indicates towards a specific time period. So there's past tense verb, he did that. He hit. Right? That's talking
[SPEAKER_00] about the past. Right? He is hitting. Right? That's in the present. Right? He will hit. That's in the? Future. Right? Future. So whenever you use a verb, it's indicating towards some time period. Okay? Then you have a Hav. Hav. Something called a Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. Hav. So if you're using a verb, it's over simplifying, because a lot of things in Arabic that are Hav, but they're not a preposition. Did you get it? That's why preposition's not a perfect translation of a Hav. A particle is a more accurate pronunciation. So what is a particle? What is a Hav? Basically, it does not indicate towards any particular thing or
[SPEAKER_00] an act, but they assist to tell us how things relate to one another. Right? on for example this the pen the pen the marker is on the board right so now it's it's not a person place for a thing it's not a verb it's an action it's telling us through the way one thing relates to another right okay so or how acts relate to things they connect the other words in a sentence together by telling us that the book for example is on the table or the pen is under the table such words are called particles in Arabic people speak of talk in singular and fool in the portal right again this is just a concept don't get too confused because we get to the actual example of all that would be much easier but the main thing you could say is like a miscellaneous category right it's not an islamic on now it's not a fair kind of verb so it's going to be a particle hub it's like miscellaneous it's things that are like putting everything together understand and we're
[SPEAKER_00] going to learn a heart I think in the next lesson we already learned a couple of powerful actually um yeah exactly very good so what we learned what which is a powerful out aren't we a number we've talked about the definition it's a powerful out so it's an example of a particle and how it connects the sentence you get it right so good so that's one and another we learned is ah right ah right that's part of this different so that's also but again don't get too confused this categorization you know reason I'm mentioning it now is because of what we're going to talk about right now okay so now for now we're not going to talk about this this half of this whole two-thirds of this whole equation right we're only talking about this right now right this is okay now when a sentence in Arabic starts with an ism that sentence is called
[SPEAKER_00] Jumna Ismiyyah right it's called Jumna Ismiyyah again if you want to remember terminology it's not a big deal as long as you know what we're talking about okay Gjumlaa is冷 is a sentence It basically is referring back to ism right so posting a construct and数 it was locked. Please make sure youity is so noted! it is a sentence that starts with A and ism, right? I don't know how the perfect translation for this would be, but basically it's a sentence that starts with an ism, okay? So all of the sentences that we did so far, they all fall under الجملة الاسمية, okay? Alright, now why is it important? Because every جملة اسمية has a general
[SPEAKER_00] composition, right? A general way that it's put together. And it's the same thing in English as well. In English, you have the subject and the predicate, right? You guys learn about this in English? Subject and the predicate, right? For example, the man is walking. So the man is the subject, right? The subject is the thing that's being talked about. You're giving information about that thing. And talking is? The information, the predicate that you're giving the information about. You're giving the information. You get it? Everybody understand that? Alright? So in the same way in Arabic you have the subject and the predicate, which is called مُبْتَدَةً خَضَى. Right? So for example, over here, now in all these sentences that we've been saying, for example, الْقَلَبُ مَكْسُورٌ Right? Now الْقَلَبُ, let's erase this. Everybody got this now? I can erase this?
[SPEAKER_00] See, normally a lot of teachers would have started with this right from the first day. But if we started from this right away, wouldn't we be able to also confuse? Now at least we have some idea, some reference points, because we've already done a couple of lessons, so we have vocabulary under our belt. We know some rules. So now we can kind of connect the dots a little bit. But as we go on, if this is too much, if it seems too, too theoretical, don't worry, inshallah. Everything will fill in itself as we move on, inshallah. As I mentioned to you, there's going to be a point where everything just clicks. Right now, just imagine it as a puzzle. Right? Imagine a puzzle that you've never seen a bigger picture. Normally, when you're putting together a puzzle, then they also give you a picture that this is going to be the end result. So then you have an idea about how you're putting it together. Imagine you learning Arabic as you're putting together a puzzle, but you haven't seen the big
[SPEAKER_00] picture yet. So you're putting it together, at one point, you're going to be like, oh, this is what it is. Right? When the puzzle gets much closer to completion, that's when you start realizing, oh, this is actually a picture of, for example, the Empire State Building or something. Right? So that point will come, inshallah. So don't get kind of confused. I see a lot of blank faces right now. Like before it was fun. You know, we were all talking about this, this is our house, this is our house. You know, it was fun, right? Now all of a sudden, all the parodies, all the parodies, like staring at me, like what's going on? Okay. So, now, Jumlah, Bismillah. Right? Yes. Which means? The sentence that starts with an ism. Okay? Now, generally, this sentence follows a structure which is مُبْتَدَةً خَبَرًا So we give the example of القلم مكسور القلم مكسور
[SPEAKER_00] القلم مكسور القلم مكسور Right? This is the مُبْتَدَة Right? It's the subject. I mean, this is the thing that you're talking about. Okay? The subject is the thing that you're talking about. The thing that you're giving information about. Right? Okay. Sorry. I know you're not so great. Okay? So, القلم is the subject, the مُبْتَدَة the thing that we're talking about. If you were to just say القلم the pen, is that conveying a full sentence? No. No. You have to give some information about it in order for it to be a complete sentence to express a complete thought. Right? And it should be something that's
[SPEAKER_00] new to the listener. Right? Otherwise, there's no point of saying the sentence. Right? If the person already knew it, then you would be like, okay, what was the point of you talking? Right? So, that's why the خبر is something that you're giving them new information. Right? مَكْسُور خبر In Urdu, what does خبر mean? News. News. News. Right? So, it's kind of similar to every example. It just means like information in general. Right? So, if those know Urdu, a lot of times they're, these words in Arabic are very similar, so it helps you to remember this. Right? So, خبر gives you information about the مُبْتَدَ. Right? Even in Urdu, you have اِبْتِدَ. What does اِبْتِدَ mean? Start. مُبْتَدَ comes from the same root. مُبْتَدَ مُبْتَدَ comes first. Right? In a sentence. And it's the subject. It's the main point of the sentence. And خبر is giving you information about the مُبْتَدَ.
[SPEAKER_00] Right? This is a predicate in English. That's the radical term for it. Okay? Now, generally speaking, again, this is, we're going to have a lot of exceptions later on, but right now is not the time to learn exceptions. Right now, we learn a general rule. Generally speaking, the مُبْتَدَ will be, should I, yeah, we were getting another one actually. Generally speaking, the مُبْتَدَ will be something which is known, right? Now, this is another category we're about to learn right now. Right? Which is things that are known versus things that are unknown. Right? So, that's where now ال comes in. Right? We were looking at ال, we were wondering why is it that ال is being added and that the م is being taken away. Right? So, unless the thing is a proper noun, proper noun means what?
[SPEAKER_00] Specific. Remember we were explaining in the beginning. Specific. Specific person. Like it's a name or محمد or something like that. If it's not a proper noun and it has a تنوين on it, then that means it is something which is unknown or in a proper terminology you would say it's indefinite. Right? So, how do I put that? So, this is indefinite, right? Or unknown. So, when you say, let me just explain a little bit. If you have to go, you can go. If, if you have a lot of people other than something, it means the. Right? That means it's something that you know about already. Right? So, for example, for example, you ask somebody, let's say somebody came and you're like, oh, did you bring the book? So, if they already had their mind rate told and for example, oh, can you, when you come for Saddam Hussein, can you bring me the Arabic book? Now, you're talking to them like, oh, can you bring, did you bring the book? Now, let's say you forgot. You're like, what book? Right? And let's say somebody came
[SPEAKER_00] to you and they told you that, um, you know, for example, one brother here, he asked me that, oh, if you have any good books for me to read, can you please bring me one from your library because I want to read on board. Right? So then, he would say, did you bring me a book? Because it's not any specific book. It's an unknown book. Right? So it's unspecific. That's why that would be called in Arabic, nakira. That would be indefinite. That would be, I would have a tanween on it. Right? But, if you were asking about a specific book, that book that you had in mind, right, then you would say, do you have the book? Right? Because it's a specific book, it's a known book that you have in mind. Right? Um, now let's say, for example, another example, right? A man. Right? Um, if you say like, uh, there was a man, like, oh, I saw a man outside the house. Right? Then
[SPEAKER_00] it's clear to the listener that it's something, it was unknown. It's just a random person. It's a man. Right? Um, but if you say, I saw the guy outside, hey, like you run to your wife, like, hey, I saw that guy, the guy outside the house. So, that means there was somebody that you guys were talking about before, maybe some guy you guys were suspecting of, you know, like stealing something from the house or something like that. But, it's somebody that you've already spoken about, it's known. You get it? That's the difference between the and a. Right? So that's exactly the difference between things that have al in Arabic and things that have the mean. Understand now? Everybody see the difference? Yeah. Okay? So, things that are known or definite in the technical terminology, that's called ma'rifah. Okay? Again, you don't need to worry too much about the terminology for now, although, inshallah, when we move progress, then it will come in handy.
[SPEAKER_00] Ma'rifah is known as known, and al is used generally, al is used to indicate that something is known. Got that? Alright. And nakira is something which is unknown and indefinite, and generally, broadly speaking, tanweed is used for that. Tanweed means there are two dalmas, right? Or, that's why I said we're not using the dalma, right now we're only on dalma, right? So that's generally, right? The one
[SPEAKER_00] that's one exception is, as I mentioned, proper nouns. Proper nouns means a specific person, a name, right? For example, Muhammad. You would say Muhammadun, you can now use that as a mukhtar, because it's something which is known, because a proper noun is already indicating towards something which is known, right? If you use a person's name, that's somebody who's already known, you're referring to a specific person. So that would also fall under this category, right? Ma'rifah. So you don't have to have al over there, in that context. Understand? That's the exception to the rule. The general rule is, if something is ma'rifah, then that means it has al, which means the. Otherwise, it'll have nakira, which is unknown or indefinite, which will have the mean. Everybody understand that? Is it confusing or everybody got it? Okay? Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Let me just write the exception.
[SPEAKER_00] So these are generally, again, obviously more, we're oversimplifying around with us because we're in the beginning. So things that have al or if they're a proper noun, that's going to be ma'rifah, right? And things that have tanween are generally going to be nakira, unless they're proper nouns. I said things that have al in general are going to be proper nouns. Sorry. Things that have al in general are going to be known. They're going to be ma'rifah. And things that have tanween are going to be nakira. And the only exception is the proper noun because they will have tanween on them many times. For example, sa'imun, right? When you're saying ma'rifah, you're saying sa'imun. Okay? Sadeemun.
[SPEAKER_00] Sameerun. Right? So all these names, mukhtarun. So all these names will have a tanween. Umaru is an exception, but we'll learn why that's an exception. And Abdullah also is an exception, but again, we'll learn those. But generally, a lot of these proper nouns will have tanween, but don't get fooled and think that those are indefinite because it's a name. It's referring to a specific person. So when somebody says, did sa'im come, even if it has a tanween, does that mean that it's a random person? No. It's a specific person because it's a name of a person. Everybody understand that point? Yeah. Okay. So, now that we learned this general rule that this is a mukhtara, this is a khabba, right? So the mukhtara, the general rule that we mentioned is that it's going to be ma'rifah. Okay? And the khabba, generally, is going to be nekira. Now,
[SPEAKER_00] what's the wisdom behind that? Again, I mentioned that if you're not telling something about the mukhtara that the person doesn't know then it's pointless, right? So that's why it makes sense that the khabba is going to be nekira, something which is unknown. Because the whole point of a sentence is to give information about something that's already known, right? Now, let's say, for example, I tell you guys, oh, Abdul Qadir is smart. What would the first question in your mind be? Who's Abdul Qadir? Right? So, that's why the thing that you're talking about should also be known to the people. So that's like the wisdom as to why something you can just think of when you're trying to remember which one is ma'rifah, which one is nekira. Just remember that the thing that you're talking about, the mukhtara, is supposed to be a thing that you already know about. That's why it's going to be ma'rifah. And the information you're giving about it is going to be, nekira is going to be,
[SPEAKER_00] unknown or indefinite. Everybody got that point? So with some revision, you read that lesson that I sent, inshallah, things will become hopefully clear, and we'll drill this concept in, inshallah. And besides that, what I want you guys to do is read the whole lesson today. I want you guys, okay, sorry, one more thing, but the class is kind of late now. Can I just add one point or do you want to end now? Sorry? Just one point, right? So, al-qalamu means the pen. Maqsurun means broken. If you were to translate it, how would you translate it? Where did you get is from? Where is is in the sentence? Yeah, but the thing is, yeah. So, it is just, it's just this. This is this. This is And this is this. No, so the word, in Arabic, there
[SPEAKER_00] is no such thing as is or am, right? It's understood from the context. You get it? So, in this context, when it's a jumlah ismiyah and it's in this structure, it's buftala and khabar, right? It's a subject and predicate. You fill in the blanks with is yourself, right? Now, inshallah, we're going to learn something later called musul sifah. And in that scenario, we'll learn that you don't include is. But we'll understand that at that point, inshallah. So, when the brother said, this is the broken pen, there's actually an incorrect translation of this. If you were to say the broken pen, then that would be al qalam al maksul. You get it? But over here, you're saying al qalam al maksul when the pen is broken, right? So, inshallah, we'll learn the trickery of that later on. But hopefully everybody got the general idea. So now, now you know how to translate all the sentences, right? You add is from your own side, and yeah, so you translate al ba'du, and it's
[SPEAKER_00] pretty straightforward. So I want everybody, your homework is to, okay, we don't know the meanings of these, right? Or do we know all these meanings? Okay, jadeelun and qadeelun. Okay, some of these words are new, so I don't want to just do this whole bunch of words, we're already kind of late. So, what I'll do is, I'll, okay, I'll give you permission to, to look in the English side for today. Sorry? No? Alright, if you want to do that, then I'll actually just post the meanings in the group right now, when I get home. Sorry? Oh, you're not in the group? Oh, did somebody add brother in the group? Hello, Debreel. Okay, good job. Alright, so homework is, I'm going to give, we're going to give the vocabulary in the group, if not, you can check the vocabulary, I'll give you permission to do just for this one time, check the back of the book, the English part, for lesson three, check the vocabulary, but
[SPEAKER_00] don't check the translation, just check the vocabulary, it says and it tells the meaning of the vocabulary, so just check that only, not the lesson itself, and then I want you to translate all, the entire lesson, okay? Alright? So homework is to translate the entire lesson, and then, based on the rules that we learned today, also, the homework is to read the lessons that I had sent in the group this morning, and just remember, there's a lot to take in, so I'm not going to give too much homework, remember all the things that we went over in this lesson, there's a lot of theories, right? So I want you guys to remember what is the ism eradik haf, right? And then, the things that fall under ism, try to remember those things, if you go over with one of your partners, or one of your classmates, it will help to put these things to solidify themselves, inshallah. So, is tamari an inclusion in that? We're going to be that guy who asked the question? No,
[SPEAKER_00] we'll leave it out for now. Don't do the means for that. Just the lesson. Just the lesson itself, not the means. Okay. Yeah, all right. On the other hand, you can write one on the next. You can write that in the email. All right. Before you roll the question, can you move over to this next one? Can you move over to the next one? Yeah, go ahead. Go ahead. Thank you.